KRISTEN DERGOUSOFF

Software Developer/Baking Enthusiast

(She/Her)

CONTACT

306-222-2073

kristen.dergousoff@gmail.com

Saskatoon, SK, Canada

linkedin.com/in/kristendergousoff



EDUCATION

M.Sc. Computer Science, Human Computer Interaction University of Saskatchewan 2013 - 2015

B.Sc. Honours, Computer Science University of Saskatchewan 2006 - 2013

SKILLS

Great communication

Excellent interpersonal and intrapersonal skills

Passionate about user experience
Enthusiastic learner of new technologies
Thrives on constructive feedback
Bakes a mean cherry pie

Python/PyQt

UX/Usability Design
Git

Figma

SOL

React

SUMMARY

Wearing many hats during my time at Siemens has given me a breadth of experience and helped to develop a broad assortment of skills that are an asset to growing teams. Working in an agile, startup-style environment has given me insight into the needs of different stakeholders and experience communicating with multiple teams to deliver creative solutions for complex evolving customer requirements.

I enjoy the human side of software development as much as I enjoy the technical side and would be well suited to a position that involves interaction with other developers, teams, and stakeholders.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Siemens EDA

Product Development Manager

APRIL 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

- Managed and grew a team of 6 software developers working across two product lines.
- Worked with customers to determine their needs and to ensure we were building the proper solutions.
- Performed first stage interviews with applicants for the product development teams.
- Introduced a user experience review process for our development teams to ensure that we maintained consistency across all products and to ensure we maintained the ease of use that we were known for in the industry.
- Conducted usability testing on a new product line to determine necessary work prior to release.

Software Developer/Senior Software Developer

JANUARY 2015 - APRIL 2021

- Managed an initial customer account during the creation of our second product line, ensuring that our tools would suit their needs. Involved continuous communication sharing development results, implementing features and bug fixes, gathering requirements, and setting up next steps.
- Mentored new employees including organising work, introducing them to our products, and bringing them up to speed on our processes.
- Consulted for developers across all teams who had questions regarding design, user experience, or our UI framework (PyQt).
- Provided designs to handle complicated user experiences within our tools.
- Delivered projects including integration with third party tools, improvements to our UIs so they remain responsive handling large data, and improvements to our tools for users with colour vision deficiencies.
- Participated in community outreach involving numerous career fairs, giving office tours, and participating in the 2019 Ladies in Tech panel.

JEFF DYCK

Senior Director of Engineering Siemens EDA jeff_dyck@mentor.com 306-262-4478

MEGAN MARSH

Senior Product Development Manager Siemens EDA megan_marsh@mentor.com 306-280-3967

JAMES COOPER

Principal Software Developer Siemens EDA james@coopercs.ca 306-260-7952